In the next domain, we are going to cover the OSI model and talk about layers on the OSI model.
In relation to that, there are two types of switches we can use: layer 2 and layer 3 switches. Earlier I mentioned that switches use MAC addresses to control traffic.
Any switch I connect to will learn this MAC address and use it to send traffic to this device. That is a layer 2 switch. What switches do not do is route traffic between networks.
For this, you need a router, or a layer 3 switch, also known as a multilayer switch.
That type of switch can use IP addresses, the logical address of this device, to route traffic between networks.
That's the major difference between a layer 2 and a layer 3 switch. For the exam, you also just need to be aware of security options for a switch.
Basically, switches use MAC tables to learn MAC addresses of devices connected to the switch.
In most cases, if no traffic is generated on a connection, these entries will erase themselves from the MAC table in due time.
One thing you can control on a managed switch is the number of addresses each switch port will memorize.
If, for example, you only allow one address per port, this will help prevent someone from connecting a rogue device to the network and sending traffic through the switch,
because that switch will realize, Hey, you're not the MAC address I have down for you on this port, and will not allow that traffic.